How come you kept the half door?
你為什麼要留著這半個門呢
Most people got rid of them.
大部分的人都會直接拆掉他們
Well ehm… I don't know
嗯...其實我也不知道
… It keeps out hens.
... 不過這樣母雞就不會跑進來啦
Of course.
也是啦
You know… And it would keep out a breeze.
而且阿...它還可以擋風
You'd have to put up a porch if you took it.
有了這個，我也不需要一整個走廊就很舒適
Yeah, true.
嗯，也對
Mmmm.
嗯嗯
And that door I think is there all the time.
而且這半扇門好像從很久以前就有了
Well it looks it.
看得出來
It's a great looking door.
它其實也滿好看的
Mmmm.
嗯嗯
So the hens do try to come in ?
所以母雞們會試著跑進來囉？
Oh they'd love to come in.
喔對阿它們總是很想進來
For the warmth ?
因為房子裡比較溫暖？
Ah yeah, and ramble around… You know.
對阿 然後可以進來亂晃阿 你懂的
And the ducks don't try to come in at all ?
那鴨子都沒有想要進來嘛？
No.
沒有耶
No?
沒有？
They're more cautious.
他們比較謹慎一點
Yeah ?
真的嘛？
Yeah.
對阿
Do you ever remember painting the furniture
妳還記得妳曾經為了不同的場合和目的
for different occasions ?
為這些家具上漆或彩繪嘛？
Well an odd time you would,
嗯..真的很偶爾你才會去
you might paint chairs…
對這些家具彩繪或是上油漆
… Although they didn't get any paint.
...雖然這幾個都沒有被畫到啦
Those chairs have been there a while. Have they ?
這些椅子也有些年代了吧？
Yeahhhh.
是阿
How far back in your family does this dresser go ?
這個碗櫃在你們家有多久的歷史啦？
Ahmm…
嗯....
… I reckon it goes back to my grandmother…
我估計應該是從我奶奶那一代...
Her name was Mary Coen.
她叫 Mary Coen
The dresser was in the house
這個碗櫃在我們家
till… Ehm… About…
一直到....大概...
…2003.
2003年吧...
On the very top here
在最上面的一層以前放著
there was 2 Willow pattern dishes.
有兩個柳樹圖樣的盤子
On this here now there was
然後在這邊的是
two smaller dishes - Willow pattern.
是兩個比較小的盤子，也是柳樹圖樣
… There was all the mugs hanging along here.
然後這邊有很多馬克杯
… On hooks.
掛在這邊
The big plates was here…
大盤子在這邊...
… And the small plates was on the bottom
小盤子在底層...
… But there was cups here…
這裡有些杯子
… There was a row of cups here…
這裡有整排的杯子
… And a row of mugs below.
下面還有一串馬克杯
Why did it go out ?
為什麼丟掉呢？
Aah… Because Johnny got
ㄜ...因為Johnny
another cabinet…
得到了另一個碗櫃...
… And I got mad.
然後我有點生氣
But you… You had moved out at that stage.
不過你後來就離開了對嗎?
I had gone… I was gone since
我後來就離開了...從
… I was gone since 1973.
1973年我就離開了...
Una Costello has a flour bin,
Una Costello 有一個麵粉櫃
and my uncle has a flour bin almost identical…
然後我叔叔也有一個幾乎一樣的麵粉櫃
and they're... They're all done in wood graining.
而且他們上面都會有清楚的木紋
Oh God, I'd… I'd have made that now.
阿...是阿...有機會我也會做一個這樣的
You would have made the flour bins ?
你會想做一個麵粉櫃？
I would, t'would be
我有想過，它會是
about that height…
大概這麼高...
… And a little board upon the top.
然後會有個板子在上面
And a lid this way you could lift up.
然後有個可以翻開的蓋子
Yes… I made that…
對，我會做一個
Were they a speciality of yours ? …
製作麵粉櫃算是
… The flour bins.
你的專長嘛？
Ah no, you'd just get an order.
也不是啦 只是接到訂單
At that time mice used to be in the houses.
那時候老鼠會出現在房子裡
They were more common that time in old houses…
以前他們在老房子滿常見的...
… And the the
因為這樣...
the flour bin was a security.
麵粉櫃就像保險箱一樣
Hmmm… Aye.
嗯....唉
Where was the dresser ?
這餐具櫃以前在哪邊？
It was in the old kitchen at home.
它原本在家裡的舊廚房
T'was a timber partition behind the dresser.
在餐具櫃後面有個隔板
Myself and my brother Jimmy
我和我弟以
slept in there behind that.
前就睡在那個後面
You know.
就是...
The flour bin was over
麵粉櫃是在
on the back wall.
靠著後面的牆
Ehm…
嗯..
I'd say,
我猜它
I'd say that was made in the late 50's.
應該是50年代晚期做的
That's quite late for a flour bin -isn't it ?
這製造年代算很晚期了耶，對嘛？
Yes, yes. The other one was gone,
嗯 另一個麵粉櫃已經丟了
the lid of it… The hinges were broken…
它的蓋子...還有鎖鏈都壞了
… And… T'was gone quite old.
它其實被用了很久
I don't know what age t'would be.
我不知道它到底年代有多久遠
Projects come in bit by bit… You know.
其實...每個東西都是一步一步完成的
Mikey Parkinson gave me a tree below in Slevoyre…
Mikey 給了我一棵在Slevoyre那邊的樹...
And I said I'd make him a table. Out of the tree.
我就跟他說我會用這棵樹做張桌子給他
So when I made one table I made six tables
說是說一張 但我其實作了六張
… And I gave him one of them.
然後我把其中一張給他
What was the wood ?
那是什麼木呢？
Beech.
櫸木
And was it hard to work with ?
會很難動工嘛？
No, beech is very nice…
不會，
Very easy to work with beech.
櫸木是很好製作的木頭
I mean for you now…
那對你來說
What was the major problem
整修舊家具
in terms of restoring the dressers?
最大的困難在哪邊？
Bad timber
木頭舊了
… Old decayed timber… Woodworm.
木頭老了 或是生蟲了
Ehm,
還有...
bad joints…
連接的地方...
… Everything very very rustic.
接的不好或設計很差...
Which… Aah… You'd be inclined to say
有時你會想說...
« It should be put together better ».
它原本可以被做的更好的...
But when it goes… When…
不過當這
It's part of the furniture then
只是家具的一小部分
and you don't mind it.
的時候你不會注意到
Tell me what you think of… Ehm
請說說你對於 嗯...
…. This traditional furniture.
這些傳統家具的看法
Aah, at first I'd have steered clear.
哈哈 其實一開始我有點想躲
Ehm…
畢竟...
I'd have sooner started with
用新的木板
a fresh piece of timber
我可以做的更快
...and worked from scratch
從刨木開始...
..and make a new piece of furniture.
然後做一件新的家具...
But ehm…
但是 嗯..
Then when Tony brought the few bits…
當Tony 拿來這幾件...
and he said sure « there's not much to do »…
當然他那時說 [這些應該也不能幹嘛...]
and we started going into dressers that
然後我們開始修這些
« wasn't much to do on them »
[也不能幹嘛]的碗櫃
… And we done a good bit on em.
...結果我們動了一點手腳，沒想到
And they turned out lovely.
最後他們變得很好看，
And I was amazed myself the way they finished up…
完成的時候我也嚇一跳
… And the way they turned out…
從翻新的結果
… And with a small bit of work
加上一點點技巧
… And a little bit… Of attention
再加上多一些用心
how you could bring them back.
可以讓他們回到原本的面貌
Cover it all up with paint afterwards so tis grand
用新塗料漆好之後它們煥然一新
- very forgiving.
我還滿欣慰的
But tell me, what is it about them that you like ?
那請告訴我，你喜歡這些舊家具的什麼呢？
… That you hadn't seen in them before ?
因為你以前並沒有看過它們吧？
Simplicity I'd say
單純簡單
… Most of it… You know.
大部分來說...
And just everything was put together
而且其實就只是重組而已
very, very basically.
非常非常基本
No real joints… Ehm… A lot of
他們很少釘子
… Even nails.
大部分都是卡榫 和螺絲釘
And nails would be rusted out now… Ehm
不過就算有釘子現在也鏽爛了...
… Screws would be bigger than what
當時用了一些
maybe you should have been using.
大小不太合適的螺絲
Ehm… Everything was so simple.
總之一切都很簡單原始
Just… It fulfilled what its job
他們的存在只為了...
… What it had to do in the house.
完成它們在房子裡面的使命。